为何他不在时,爱会越来越深?
Why is love intensified  by absence?
那是什么感觉?
How does it feel?
什么感觉啊?
Hmm.  How does it feel?
普普通通吧
Normal.
彷佛什么都没有
You know. Like nothing.
彷佛你稍微神游了一下
Like your attention wandered  for a moment, and...
突然间你读的书就不见了
suddenly the book you're reading  is gone,
咖啡和房间都不见了
your coffee's gone, the room is gone,
突然就掉进了水沟里
and you're ankle-deep  in a ditch...
或是在高速公路上
...or in the middle  of a highway...
该死
Oh, shit!
或是在野外的牛群之中
...or in a field full of cows.
当然了,全身是赤裸的
And of course...  ...you're naked.
不只回到过去还全身赤裸
Back in time, and naked.
床上会变得空荡荡
The bedsheets will go slack.
或莲蓬头的水会一直冲着  或是培根会放着继续煎
Or the shower will keep running,  or the bacon will keep frying,
或者会听到咖啡杯碎裂一地
or you'll hear  a coffee cup smash on the floor,
你就知道他不见了
and you realize, he's gone.
又来了
It's happened again.
只剩下一迭衣服
He's just a pile of clothes.
《时间简史》——史蒂芬·霍金 著
接着就开始了
And then it starts.
等待
The waiting.
时空旅行不是超能力
Time travel.  It's not a superpower.
是某种缺陷也是我的问题
It's a disability.  It's what's wrong with me.
我无法掌握当下而是‥
I can't keep hold  of the current moment, I just...
彷佛从手中滑落  我就回到了过去
slide off. I fall back in time.
他不见时我会等他也会担心
When he's gone,  I wait and I worry.
我不停想他在何时何地
I wonder where he is,  when he is.
他是不是有危险?
If he's in danger.
有时你会回到原本的位置
Now, sometimes you ping  straight back to where you were.
读著书或喝着咖啡  然后就没事了
You know, to your book,  to your coffee, and it's fine.
不算什么,就像睡了五分钟
It's nothing.  Five minutes, a nap.
有时长达数天,数周甚至数月
Sometimes it's days, weeks,  months,
你得想办法活下来
and you have to survive.
有三件事我变得很在行
Now, three things I got good at.
逃跑,战斗和偷窃
Running, fighting, and stealing.
这些你必须都很在行
You have to be good at those,
毕竟无论到哪里  你都浑身赤裸
when wherever you go, you're naked.
该死
Fuck.
这个问题真难回答
Well,  that's a difficult question.
你认真在问我这个问题吗?
Seriously,  you're asking me that?
我们第一次见面是什么时候?
When did we first meet?
第一次见面?
First meet?
你先定义"第一次"
Define "first."
我嫁给了一名时空旅人
I married a time traveler.
这可说来话长了
It's complicated.
本剧中英双语字幕由 雪碧居士 制作合成 全网首发
若你不是时空旅人
If you're not  a time traveler, the past
你的过去就是过去了
is what you're stuck with.
若你是艺术家  或认为可能是艺术家
If you're an artist,  or think you might be,
你要创造的是未来
the future  is what you're gonna make.
有时你能在一盆污水中看见未来
Sometimes, you can see  the future in a bowl of slop.
其他时候‥
Other times...
「克蕾儿20岁」
克蕾儿,你还好吗?
-Clare? You okay?
你知道我需要什么吗?
-You know what I need?
费曼博士  我得去一趟图书馆
Dr. Felman, I need to go  to the library.
-去吧  -是纽伯利图书馆
-Okay.  -The Newberry Library.
-那里有什么?  -色情影片
-What's there?  -Porn.
其他时候?
Other times...
其他时候你则会记得
...other times, you remember
未来总会在你的  不意中找上门
that the future is just what shows up  when you're looking for something else.
人都认为图书馆
People think
「克蕾儿20岁  亨利28岁」
是安静的地方
libraries are quiet places.
对我来说图书馆彷佛是一群人
To me a library is a crowd.
若你是时空旅人  过去不再只是过去
If you're a time traveler,  the past is alive.
过去正在发生而且也很危险
It's still happening,  still dangerous.
所有书架上的书都像笼子的铁杆
All those books  on all those shelves are like the bars on a cage,
而里头的野兽来回踱步
and the beast inside is pacing.
对其他人而言过去已逝
For everybody else,  the past is over.
对我来说  我仍试着在过去中活下来
For me, well,  I'm still trying to survive it.
这些是你的吗?
Are these yours?
我在书库中找到的
I found them in the stacks.
对,谢了
Uh... yeah, thanks.
亨利,我一直想问你  为什么总是四处乱丢衣服?
Henry. I've been meaning  to ask you. Why do you leave piles  of clothes all over the place?
-大家不都这样吗?  -才不是
-Doesn't everyone?  -No.
情况很复杂
It's complicated.
好啊,我听你说
Okay. I'm listening.
说来话长
-It's a long story.
时间于我不成问题
-Time isn't a problem for me.
你可真幸运
Lucky you.
亨利
Henry.
嘿
Hey.
(法语)
-不好意思  -你还好吗?
...the language of-- -Ah, excuse me. You okay?
对,我很好  你们在这里做什么?
Yeah, no, I'm good.  What's going down here?
展示稀有字典
Presentation  on rare dictionaries.
天啊,我很爱字典
Oh, God. I love dictionaries.
你知道字典最棒的是什么吗?
You know the best thing  about a dictionary?
唯有字典才会正确顺序排列单字
It's the only book with words  in the right order.
我们没事,谢谢你,亨利
Yeah, we're good here.  Thanks, Henry.
正确的顺序非常重要  相信我
The right order is very important. You can trust me on that.
稍等片刻  迪坦布先生也许能帮上你
If you wait just one moment,  perhaps Mr. DeTamble can help you.
谢谢你
-Thank you.
伊莎贝尔
-Ah, Isabelle?  -Hmm?
在第二展示区有名年轻女子
There is a young woman  in Presentation Two.
你能摇醒她吗?  待会儿汤姆会让她无聊透顶
Could you maybe shake her awake  when Tom's done boring her
然后假装热情叫我的名字
and kind of mention my name  with general overtones of enthusiasm?
《凯尔姆斯科特版乔叟作品集》
-The Kelmscott Press Chaucer.
-怎么了?  -你知道那是什么?
-What about it? You know what it is?
知道,配有插图的乔叟作品集
Yeah. It's Chaucer. Illustrated.
算是半个色情作品  但火车上也能读,怎么了?
Basically porn, but you're allowed to read it  on a train. Why?
那位年轻小姐想读这本色情作品
That young lady would like  to see the porn.
好吧
Okay.
你好,我能帮忙吗?
Hi. Can I help you?
《凯尔姆斯科特版乔叟作品集》  对吧?
Uh, The Kelmscott  Press Chaucer, right?
亨利?
-Henry.  -Oh...
你好‥
hello.
-抱歉,我不知道‥  -克蕾儿
-Sorry I--I don't know-- -Clare.
艾布夏尔
Abshire.
克蕾儿艾布夏尔
Clare Abshire.
你还好吗?
You okay?
大概吧,怎么了?
I think so, yeah, why?
你的表情有点奇怪
Uh, you've got a, kinda look  on your face.
什么表情?
-What kind of a look?  -Um...
我在想有没有比脑震荡好的词
Trying to think of a better word  than concussion.
抱歉,我‥
Sorry. I, uh...
我没有料到今天会遇到你
I wasn't expecting  to meet you today, um.
我是说不会在图书馆遇到你
I mean definitely not  in a library. Wh--
等等,你是图书馆员?
You're a librarian?
没错
Well...
图书馆员?
-Yeah.  -A librarian.
而且你的名字叫迪坦布?
And your name  is DeTamble.
我得花一点时间才能适应
That's gonna take  a bit of getting used to.
抱歉,我真的不太明白‥
Sorry, I-- I don't really understand--
你有一个胎记
You have a birthmark?
长得像草莓
Like a strawberry?
就好像你踩烂了一颗草莓
Like you stood on a strawberry,  and squished it?
在你的左脚上
On your left foot?
而且你的发际线下有道疤
Also, you've got a scar  just below your hairline.
你现在看不到  你头发怎么这么长
You can't see it right now,  your hair is too long.
你的头发真的很长  你故意留长的吗?
Actually, your hair  is really long. Is that on purpose?
你从未跟我说过疤痕怎么来的
You've never told me  how you got the scar.
我问过但我想你不太想谈
I've asked, but I don't think  you like talking about it.
-我们曾经见过?  -对
So, we've met then? Yes.
不对,是我见过你
Well, no. I've met you.
我十四年前见过那个胎记
I saw that birthmark  14 years ago.
我认识你十四年了
I've known you for 14 years,  and now...
但现在你却站在那里  一副从未见过我的样子
...you're standing there looking  like you've never -seen me before.
-我不曾见过你  -我知道
-I haven't.  I know.
你这么年轻
You're so young.
比我见过的你都还要年轻
You're younger  than I've ever seen you.
好,你知道为何我认不出你吗?
Okay, do you understand  why I don't recognize you?
-知道  -所以你知道我的‥
-Yes.  -So, you know about my,
问题吗?  知道
-uh, you know...  -Problem. Yes.
-谁告诉你的?  -你告诉我的
-Who told you?  -You told me.
好吧,我们不能在这里聊天  我们去喝杯咖啡吧
Okay, we can't talk here,  we should get a coffee.
-或喝一杯酒  -那就喝酒
-Or a drink.  -Okay, a drink.
-或一起吃晚餐  -进展得真快
Dinner! That escalated quickly.
十四年了
Fourteen years.
纽伯利图书馆
-那就今晚  -好啊
-So, tonight?  -Uh, yeah.
就今晚
-Yeah, tonight.  -Yeah.
-抱歉,我不知道要怎么‥  -别道歉,我也是
Sorry, I'm not exactly sure  how to-- No, me neither.
我通常满擅长解读女人心的
Usually I'm pretty good  at reading women.
-女人心?  -人心
-Women?  -Uh, people.
-不论男女  -好吧
Both.  Okay.
晚点见
Yeah, later.
不论男女
Both.
好了
All right.
-你好  -你好,你从来不曾送我花
-Hi.  -Hi. You've never brought me  flowers before.
-你觉得花有用吗?  -对什么有用?
-Do you think that's gonna work?  -Work in what sense? I mean...
我们有什么目标吗?
...what  are we trying to achieve?
这是约会吗?  我们在约会吗?
Is this a date?  Are we on a date right now?
记事本
那是什么?
What's that?
日期,有152天
Dates, 152 of them.
152天?
A hundred and fifty-two.
你打架了吗?
Have you been in a fight?
当然,不然花怎么来的?
Sure. How do you think  I got the flowers?
这是‥谁列的?
Who uh...  who wrote this list?
是我
Me. When I was a kid.  You, uh, you dictated it to me.
你在我小时候 命令我写的
我吗?
-I did?  -Mm-hmm.
这样我才知道你什么时候会出现
So, I'd know  when you'd be showing up.
几年前你告诉我  你从我给你的清单中记住这件事
Oh, you told me a few years ago  that you memorized it from the list that  I'm giving you now,
就是你一开始命令我做的事
which you dictated to me  in the first place so,
所以我不确定讯息还存不存在
I'm really not too sure  how the information even exists.
-这列表就像莫比乌斯环一样  -够了
It's just like some kind of Möbius list-- -Okay, just stop!
拜托
Please.
-说慢一点  -也是,这让人很难理解
Just slow down. Sorry, it's, uh, it's confusing.
我有比较长的时间能好好琢磨
I've had longer  to think about it.
没发生过这种事吗?
So, has this never happened  to you before?
-像是以错误的顺序遇见某人?  -没有
Like meeting someone  in the wrong order? No.
他不曾警告过你这类的事吗?
Didn't he warn you  about this kind of thing?
-谁不曾警告过我?  -训练你的人啊
-Didn't who warn me?  -The guy who trained you.
我知道有个家伙教了你时空旅行
I know there was a guy who, like taught you  all the time-travel stuff.
你小时候有另一个时空旅人  教了所有的规则
Like all the rules,  when you were little. Another time traveler.
我跟你说过那是谁吗?
-Did I tell you who it was?
目前为止还没有
-Not so far. No.
好吧
Right.
好吧,我就直说了
So...  ...getting this straight.
在未来‥在我的未来
-Hmm.  -In the future...
我会开始出现在你的过去里
...in my future I'm gonna start showing up in your past.
-没错  -十四年如此
-Yes. For 14 years.
对,高达152次
One hundred and fifty-two times.
我那时年纪多大?
Uh, how old was I? Back then?
我见过你年纪最大是四十几岁吧
I mean, oldest I've seen you  is like 40 something.
年纪最小是三十岁左右
And youngest... maybe about 30.
你现在几岁?
-How old are you now?  -Uh...
我28岁
I'm 28.
你看起来不同以往
You look so different.
就好像你整个人都瘦了  重新翻修了一样
It's like you've been all,  tightened, you know. Renovated.
那一定很奇怪吧?
-That must be kind of weird?  -Hot.
-性感  -性感?
-Hot?  -Yeah, hot.
很性感啊,某人找我约会呢
Somebody pimped my date.
-我们现在是在约会吗?  -是啊
Is that what we're doing here?  We're on a date? -Yes.
-约会的那种约会吗?  -是啊
-Like a date-date? -Yes.
-那我表现如何?  -非常出色
-Oh, how am I doing? -Astonishingly well.  -Oh.
我是说以正常人的标准来说
Well, I mean, about as well as it's possible  for a human being to do, in fact.
太好了
Great.
没有想问的了吗?
No more questions?
我突然分心了
Hmm, all of a sudden,  I'm distracted.
-专心点,问我问题  -好
Concentrate. -Ask me something.  -Okay.
为什么是你?
Why you?
为什么我会见你那么多次?
Why would I go  see you so many times?
这个问题等等再说
We're gonna have to come back  to that one.
-但背后是有原因的?  -是有原因的
-But there is a reason?  -There's a reason. Yeah.
下一个问题
Next question.
好吧
Okay, uh...
有什么嗜好或喜欢的书吗?
Any hobbies? Any favorite books?
有没有什么我该注意的  任何不常见的性癖?
Any unusual sexual proclivities  I should be aware of?
有一个
One.
是什么?
What's that?
我会和你结婚
I'm going to marry you.
我原本打算娓娓道来  但我说出来了
I was gonna build up to that.  But, uh... there it is.
我是你未来的妻子
I'm your future wife.
-谁说的?  -你啊
-Who said it?  -You do.
是你告诉我的
You told me.
你向我解释  你是从我们已婚的未来里过来的
You explained,  you were visiting me from a time in the future,  when we're married.
抱歉,我不是故意突然说这些
I'm sorry, I--I don't mean to,  uh, spring it on you like that,
不过在未来我们是一对已婚夫妻
but, in the future,  we're a married couple.
恭喜
Congratulations.
什么恭喜?
-Seriously? Congratulations?  -What--
不然我该说什么?
-What am I supposed to say?
-你太看得起自己了吧?  -我甚至不知道要回答什么‥
-Ah, you don't think much of yourself, do you? I don't know,  I can't even begin to answer  something like--
-恭喜是怎样?  -这场对话没有前情提要
-"Congratulations" though?  -There is literally no precedent -for this conversation
-当然啊  -抱歉,要消化的讯息太多了
-That's for sure. I'm sorry, it's just a lot to-- to process.
握着我的手再开口
Take my hand  when you say process.
-说真的,结婚?  -没错
-I've been married?  -Yes.
-你是我的‥  -我就是
-You're my...  -Yes, I am.
-你是我的妻子?  -没错,你未来的妻子
-You're my wife?  -Your future wife. Yes.
我们四小时前才认识  我们甚至还没点餐
I met you four hours ago,  we haven't even ordered yet.
我知道‥我真的明白‥
I know. I know. I do.  I mean I--I get it. I get it.
对我来说已经十四年了
It's like  14 years for me.
对你来说却只是今天的事
Just earlier today for you,
-真的让人难以接受  -没错
it's--it's a lot. Yeah.
所以问我问题吧
So, ask me questions.
好吧,那么‥
Okay, well.
既然我们会结婚
Seeing as we're gonna  be married, and, uh,
而且无意冒犯  这只是你的片面之词‥
no offence, I've only got  your word for that.
严格来说  我之前也只有你的片面之词
Well, technically, I've only got  your word for that,
但你若仔细想想  夫妻之间还能有什么呢?
but, if you think about it  what does any couple ever have--
-拜托别那样  -哪样?
-Please, don't do that.  -Do what?
-在我提到夫妻时咽口水  -我咽口水了吗?
Swallow, when I say  the word "couple."
没错,而且还发出声音  隔壁桌都看过来了
-Did I just swallow?  -Yeah, audibly. -The next table looked over.  -Oh.
来吧
So, come on,
问问题吧
questions.
我们怎么认识的?
How did we meet?
你是问对我来说是怎么样吗?
You mean, how was it for me?
马克‥是你吗?
CLARE, 6: Mark. Mark, is that you?
这是我的地盘,你不该来这里
This is my place. You're not supposed  to come here.
你好,克蕾儿
Hello, Clare.
-你是谁?  -亨利啊
-Who are you?  -Well, it's Henry.
亨利?
Henry?
对,我只是觉得不舒服
Yeah, I'm just, uh,  being sick.
旅行有时会让我不舒服  你知道的
Travelling makes me sick  sometimes, you know that.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你还不认识我吗,克蕾儿?  我们还没有见过?
Uh, don't you  know me yet, Clare? Haven't we met yet?
-没有  -好吧,没关系‥
-No.  -Oh, well.
因为你现在认识我了  你知道我是你朋友
That's okay. That's okay.  Uh, 'cause you're meeting me now and you know I'm a friend, okay?
我保证我是你的朋友  我叫亨利
I promise you I'm a friend.  My name's Henry.
我没有叫亨利的朋友
I don't have any friends  called Henry.
那你现在有了
Well, you do now.
帮我个忙  拿些衣服给我,好吗?
Hey, could you do me a favor  and go and get me some clothes?
-为什么?  -因为我没有衣服
Why?  'Cause I don't have any.
我敢打赌你很会选衣服
And I bet you are amazing  at choosing clothes.
怎么在室内奔跑呢?
What's all this  running around indoors?
奈尔,你知道想象中的朋友吧?
Nell, you know  what an imaginary friend is.
-知道  -我在林子里找到了一个
-True.  -I found one in the woods
我现在要为他着装  因为他全身光溜溜
and I'm gonna dress him up  'cause he's naked.
-你好啊  -你好
-CLARE, 6: Hi.  -Hi.
-是这里  -对,只要打上地轴就可以了
So, right there. Yeah, just label it,  Earth's axis.
好的,地轴
Oh, okay. Earth's axis.
我准备好了
Okay, I'm ready.
你动作真快
-CLARE, 6: That was quick.
我的经验可多了呢
-I've had a lot of practice.
你在流血
You're bleeding.
毕竟你朝我丢了鞋子
-Well, you threw a shoe at me.
-我不会道歉  -你为何要道歉?
-I'm not saying sorry. Why should you?
-那是什么印子?  -那个只是胎记
What's that mark? Oh, that?  That's just a birthmark.
别担心,不会痛
Don't worry, it doesn't hurt.
看起来就像你踩烂了一颗草莓
It looks like you stood  on a strawberry and squished it.
别人也说过‥不对
Someone else said that. No.
-哪里不对?  -不是别人说的
-What's wrong?  -Well, it wasn't someone else.
你见过恐龙吗?
Have you seen dinosaurs?
我有次搔了恐龙的肚子
I tickled  a dinosaur's tummy once.
其实是两次  但那是在自然历史博物馆的事
Twice actually, but it was  in the Natural History Museum.
真的恐龙啦
Real ones.
我会时空旅行  但不会到那么远的过去
Well, I travel in time,  but not that far back.
我通常会到我出生后的时间里
I tend to stay in the same time  since I was born.
不就是有恐龙吗?
-Is that not dinosaurs?
不是,克蕾儿,没有恐龙
-No, Clare. That is not dinosaurs.
你未来有小孩吗?
Do you have kids in the future?
恐怕没有
No. I'm afraid not.
-你有妻子吗?  -有啊
Do you have a wife?
-她漂亮吗?  -她非常漂亮
-Yeah  -Is she pretty? -She's very pretty.
她叫什么名字?
-What's her name?
好笑的是她叫克蕾儿
Well, funnily enough,  her name's Clare.
-和我一样  -对,和你一样
-Like me.  -Yeah. Like you.
-是一见钟情吗?  -天啊,最好不要
Was it love at first sight? -God, I hope not.
你会亲她吗?
-Do you kiss her?
-我会  -为什么?
-Uh... ...yeah.  -Why?
因为感觉很好也因为我爱她
Because it's nice,  and because I love her.
为什么你喜欢亲人?
Why do you like kissing people?
你为什么要为你的马刷毛?
Why do you like brushing  your horse's hair?
我不是在刷毛,是梳毛
It's not brushing,  I'm grooming her.
好了,换个话题,克蕾儿
Okay, moving on. Uh, Clare,
再过不久我就要消失了
in a little while,  I'm gonna disappear.
-我能看吗?  -可以
-Can I watch?  -Yeah, you can.
但我要你帮我个忙
But I'd like you to do me  a little favor.
我走的时候会留下衣服
See when I go, I'm gonna leave  my clothes behind.
我想要你把它们拿走  收在安全的地方
But I'd like you to take them,  and put them somewhere safe.
也许收在这个石头下
Maybe, um, under this rock.
或是收在盒子里  衣服就能保持干燥
And if you could put them  in a box for me, -they'll be nice and dry.
你会回来吗?
-Are you coming back?
会啊,我会回来很多次
Yeah, I'll be back  lots of times.
对我来说我已经回来过几次了
Some of those times  have already happened for me,
你会发现我看起来  比较年轻或比较老
you'll see me looking younger.  Maybe older.
你不能带着自己的衣服吗?
Can't you bring  your own clothes?
我不能带任何东西,这是规则
I can't bring anything.  Those are the rules.
为什么会有规则?
Why are there rules?
-我不知道  -谁告诉你这些规则的?
-I don't know.  -Who told you the rules?
-你的问题可真多  -你说我能问的
You ask a lot of questions,  don't you? -You said I could.
我第一次时空旅行时  遇到一个‥男人
-Well, the very first time  it happened to me, -there was, uh, a man.
-是谁啊?  -另一个‥
-Who? Another...
另一个时空旅人  但是说来话长,克蕾儿
another time traveler, but,  it's a very long story, Clare.
很好,我喜欢听故事
Good. I like stories.
走吧,亨利,快要关门了
Come on, Henry.  It's closing in a minute.
-菲尔德自然史博物馆即将闭馆  -来吧,我们走吧
And Chicago's... Come on, you two. Let's go. We will be closing shortly.
走吧
-Ah!  -Let's go.
亨利,觉得如何?  第一次来博物馆,喜欢吗?
What do you think, Henry?  First museum, you like it?
他爱死了,你说是不是,亨利?
-Mm-hmm.  -Oh, he loved it. -Didn't you, Henry?  -Mm-hmm.
「亨利7岁」
-我们能再去一次吗?  -当然可以
-Can we go back?  -Of course, we can.
今晚吗?
-Tonight?
很快就可以了
-Soon.
好好睡觉
Sleep tight.
小子,亨利,穿上这个
Hey, kid! Henry. Put this on.
你时空旅行回到三小时前了
You've time traveled back,  about three hours.
前面有个垃圾桶
There's a trash can  in front of you.
我会这么说  是因为很快你就会觉得不舒服
Now, I say that because  in a minute, you're gonna be sick.
你怎么知道我会不舒服?
How did you know I'd be sick?
我也是时空旅人
'Cause I'm a time traveler, too.
「亨利7岁和28岁」
我的经验可多了呢
I've had a lot of practice.
我以为你会更吃惊
Thought you might look  a bit more surprised.
对什么吃惊?
-About what?
突然出现在这里
-Suddenly showing up here.
这是我参观的  第一个博物馆
It's my first museum.
我早就想过会梦到它了
I thought I might have a dream  about it.
抱歉,亨利,这不是梦
Sorry, Henry, no.  This isn't a dream.
-你在这里工作吗?  -我不在这里工作
-Do you work here?  -No, I don't work here.
这些衣服是我偷的  就像我为你偷那件上衣一样
I stole these clothes  like I stole you that t-shirt.
听着,我也会时空旅行
See, I time travel, too.
你回到三小时前,我回到‥
You came back about three hours.  I came back, uh...
-你说说这是哪一年?  -1987年
-Remind me, what year is this?  -1987.
回到21年前
Yeah, 21 years.
有很多时空旅人吗?
Are there lots of time  travelers?
大家伙,在上面过得如何?
Hey, big guy.  Hey, how you doing up there?
看我搔痒你‥
Tickle, tickle, tickle.
它不太怕痒呢
He's not really ticklish,  is he?
你想试试吗?  过来吧
You wanna try? Come on.
真没幽默感,难怪都灭绝了
No sense of humor.  No wonder they all died out.
我什么时候会见到  其他时空旅人?
When do I meet the other ones?  The other time travelers.
你现在饿了吧?
You're hungry now, right?
时空旅行总让人饿肚子,来吧
Time travel always makes you  hungry. Come on.
好了,吃吧
Okay. Eat up.
过不了多久你又会不舒服
In a minute you're gonna feel  a little sick again
接着就会回到家了,就是这样
and then you're gonna snap  right back home. That's how it works.
好吧
Okay.
今天开始我会教你
So. Today's the day,  I'm gonna start teaching you.
我真的觉得我变得成熟稳重了呢
I must be feeling very grown up.
我要怎么回家?
How do I get back home?
自然就会回家的
It'll just happen.
有时你不一定会直接回去
Sometimes you don't go  straight back.
而是先到了另一个时空
You go to another time first.
有次我连续去了三个不同的时空
Once I went  to three different times in a row,
但通常你都会直接回家
but mostly you ping  straight back home.
-那我能去未来吗?  -有时可以
-Can I go to the future, too?  -Yeah. Sometimes.
虽然不常但还是会发生
Not so often, but it happens.
那我们怎么办?
What do we do?
我们怎么办是什么意思?
What do you mean,  "What do we do?"
我们是时空旅人  我们会处理犯罪案件吗?
We're time travelers.  Do we solve crimes?
不会,亨利,抱歉了
Uh, no, Henry, sorry.
我们不会处理犯罪案件  而是会犯案
We don't solve crimes,  we... ...commit them.
我们会逃跑,偷窃和战斗
We run, we steal, we fight.
我们时空旅行时  都全身赤裸而且不舒服
Wherever we show up in time,  we're naked... ...and we're sick.
我们别无选择
We don't get a choice.
我们是坏蛋吗?
Are we the bad guys?
活下来的通常都是坏蛋
Survivors are always  the bad guys.
所以我才要教你如何变成大坏蛋
That's why it's my job, to teach you how to be  the baddest guy out there.
所以我还会再见到你
So, I'm gonna see you again?
对,很多次
Yeah, lots of times.
-你保证?  -我保证
-Do you promise?  -Yeah, I promise.
其实我正好在你这个年纪时
In fact, when I was your age,  exactly your age,
有个人回到那个时刻训练了我
there was a guy who came back  in time and he trained me.
现在轮到我训练你了
So now,  it's my turn to train you.
所以有很多我们这种人
So, there's lots of us?
没错
Yeah.
-有我们这种时空旅人很多  -那就好
There's lots of us  time travelers. Good.
我会训练你  听起来如何,亨利?
How does that all sound, Henry?  Me training you.
很可怕
Scary.
这世界很可怕
Well, the world's a scary place.
所以你知道要怎么办吗?
So, you know what you gotta be?
你得变得更可怕
You gotta be scarier.
等等,我突然好像不这么想了
Yeah, suddenly I'm not sure.  I think that...
今天还真是成熟稳重的一天啊  我这是怎么了?
I am having a very grown-up day.  What is up with that?
没事,你这是要回家了  下次见
It's okay. You're going home. Next time.
好了
Okay.
该死
Oh, shit.
该死,你们继续,别管我
Oh, shit. Carry on.  Don't mind me.
-你在搞什么鬼?  -等我一下‥好吗?
What the fuck are you doing? Now, just--just give me  a moment, okay?
搞什么鬼?
What the fuck?
你能说说现在的日期跟时间吗?
Yeah. Could you give me the date  and the time, please?
-你在说什么?  -我只要日期和时间就好
-What are you saying?  -Uh, just the date and the fucking time,  that's all I need.
惨了,这波很猛烈
Oh, shit. This is gonna be  a big one--
-6月26日  -谢谢
-Uh... June 26.  -Thank you.
-现在晚上8点15分  -闭嘴,别跟他说话
Yeah, it's 8:15 p.m. Shut up talking to him.
-他连衣服都没穿  -2008年?
He's naked! 2008?
好吧‥我离开了两小时
Huh, okay, okay. That's uh...I've been gone two hours,
-我的衣服不可能还在这里  -你的衣服?
my clothes won't still be here. Your clothes?
我需要你的衣服
I'm gonna need yours.
你需要什么?
-You're gonna need what?
受伤的会是你,不是我
-This is gonna hurt. You, not me.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
你叫什么?
What's your name?
-丹娜  -丹娜
-Donna. Uh, Donna.
接下来,我要拿走  你男友的衣服后离开
What's gonna happen now  is I'm gonna take your boyfriend's clothes  and just go.
你可以把他摆好位置让他休息  并且报警
If you like, you can put him  in the recovery position and call the cops.
尽可能向他们描述我
Give them  my description by all means,
但我全身赤裸  你会发现竟然难以记得细节
but I'm naked, you'll find  details surprisingly difficult to remember.
那些花是他送你的吗?
Did he give you those flowers?
-对  -真好
-Yeah.  -Oh, that's nice.
他看起来不像这种人
He doesn't seem like the type.
既然他挺混蛋而且约会也毁了
Seeing as he's kind  of an asshole and this is a shitty date anyway.
介意我拿走花吗?
Mind if I take them?
我赴约已经迟到了
I'm late for someone.
-你好  -你好,你从来不曾送我花
-Hi.  -Hi. You've never brought me  flowers before.
-你觉得花有用吗?  -不是,我只是认为‥
-Do you think that's gonna work?  -No, I just think
花能为你的公寓增色
that your apartment  might be a bit nicer.
-你的公寓不好吗?  -那是我住的公寓
-Well, what's wrong with yours?  -Well, I live in it.
我的生活乱七八糟  乱到像是一处养着人的农场
I live really badly in it,  it's like a farm for one human.
真好笑,我认识你这么久了
You know it's funny,  I've known you almost all my life
你却和我想象的不太一样
and you're not what  I was expecting.
-我让你失望了?  -不是‥
Am I a disappointment? No, no. Oh,
你只是‥很独特
you're just uh-- Well, you're different.
好的还是坏的独特?
Well, different good or bad?
就是很独特
Just different.
不会吧,变得更糟糕了
Oh, no. It's got a lot worse.
你数数到一百万
You are gonna have to count  to a million.
85,86,87,88  89,90
Eighty-five,  86, 87... ...88, 89, 90,
-快点  -继续数数
hurry up. -Keep counting.
-天啊,都十四年了  -快点数数
-Jesus! Fourteen years. Count, come on.  Count, count, count.
你人还在吗?
-You still there?
对,再一分钟,快数数
-Yeah, one more minute. -Count, come on.
90‥我数到哪边‥97,98
-Ninety--I mean where? What?
99,100,101,102
-99, 100.  -Shit.
这才不是大人的公寓
This is not the apartment  of a grown-up.
这么说不公平
Oh, that's not fair.
我头一次这么像个成熟的大人
This is the most grown-up  I've ever been.
一直以来都是我先主动
Always been me  who makes that move.
是吗?  以后再也不是了
Yeah, it never will be again.
等等,这是我想的那个吗?
Wait, is that what I think  it is?
对,那是我的一颗乳牙
Oh, yeah. That's one  of my baby teeth.
你会留着乳牙?
-Wait, you kept your baby teeth?
不是,它自己出现了
-No, it just appeared.
一分钟后就会回到枕头底下  从小就是如此
It'll go in a minute.  Back under my pillow from when I was a kid.
我的每个部分都会时空旅行  连我的指甲屑都是
All of me time travels.  Even my nail clippings.
-真恶心  -你知道什么更恶心吗?
-Hmm, that's gross.  -You know what's even grosser?
剪下的头发会跟着你回家
The haircut  that follows you home.
所以你才留长发吗?
-Is that why you keep it long?
我喜欢留长,而且有时‥
-Well, I like it long. And, uh, sometimes...
我应该警告你一下  有时会见血
I should probably  warn you about this, sometimes there's blood.
就是一滩血  代表某时某地的我受了伤
Just, like, a pool of blood.  Which means somewhere out there, in another time,  I've been hurt,
-或是我流了鼻血‥  -我知道
or, you know,  maybe I got a nosebleed-- I know.
-等等,你怎么知道?  -我‥
-Wait, you know. How?  -I, uh, one time, I--
-有次我猜你‥  -别说了‥
-I assumed-- -Uh, no. Stop, stop, stop.
若这是我还不该知道的事  我最好别知道的好
If it's something I'm not  supposed to know yet, it's... probably best I don't.
这就是你上次跟我说的话
That's what you said  the last time.
那个我做得真好
Good old me.
为什么你都不会吓坏?
Why aren't you  permanently terrified?
人都会流血吧?
There's always gonna  be days that you bleed, right?
这个道理适用于所有人  不是只有我
That's true  for everyone, not just me.
你能做的就是庆幸  不是今天流血
All you can do is be happy  it's not today.
亨利,不会是今天的
-Henry.  -Yeah. It's not today.
还真是强势啊
Wow, she's forceful, isn't she?
我决定我们要转换一下心情
Mm-hmm. Well, I decided we need  a change of mood.
-你想要什么都会得手吗?  -都会得手
Yeah. Do you always get  what you want? Oh, always, I mean,
我很讨人厌,但是没关系  你也很讨人厌
I am horrible. It's okay, you're horrible, too.
-我很讨人厌吗?  -没错
-I'm horrible?  -Yeah.
你十四年来从未踰矩过
You have been a perfect  gentleman for 14 years.
-确定那是我?  -对
-Are you sure that was me?  -Yeah, homework,
做作业,玩桌游,说真心话
-Yeah, homework,board games, heart-to-hearts,
背法语单字和玩跳棋
board games, heart-to-hearts,  French verbs, and checkers.
在饥渴难耐的青春期里  你的陪伴简直让我受不了
You have been unbearable company
爱情来得太快
throughout a very horny adolescence.
-毕竟你那时还小  -是啊
Well, you know, you were a kid.
我不是长大了吗?
Haven't I grown?
而且不只我长大了
I'm not the only one.
-你这么认为?  -对啊
-You think?  -Yeah.
长得高到不需要家长陪同  也能搭乘迪斯尼的可怕设施了
I'd say, tall enough  to do the scary rides at Disney without a parent.
亨利,你真年轻
Oh, Henry! You're so young!
我要去浴室
I'm going to the bathroom.
好,就在那里
Okay. It's over there.
你若要开灯,我完全理解
I fully understand  if you put the lights on.
怎么说?
-Hmm, why?  -Hmm.
我没穿衣服
-I'm naked.
说得对,好建议,谢了
-Oh, yeah. Good tip. Thanks.
亨利,我要强调  为了将来用作参考
For the record, Henry.  For future reference,
最下层的抽屉  是我第一个看的抽屉
the bottom drawer  was the very first one  I looked in.
我不会问她的名字,我不必知道
I'm not going to ask her name,  I don't need to know.
-好吧  -那是你的破事
-Okay.  -That's your business.
你又没问我有没有女友
Uh, it's not like you  asked if I was seeing anyone.
的确,但总该提一下
Uh, yeah. But you are allowed  to mention the fact.
最好是在我们离开餐厅之后  在上床之前就说出来
Preferably somewhere between  the restaurant and the mattress.
-我选择不说的理由非常充分  -是什么?
I didn't wanna do that  for a very good reason. -Oh, which was?
我真的很想跟你上床
-I really wanted to have sex with you.
我们现在是在说笑吗?
-Oh! What, are you joking now?
-你在搞笑吗?  -一半搞笑,一半称赞
-You trying to be funny?  -Bit funny, bit flattering.
称赞我?  天啊
Flattering? Jesus!
-英格丽  -什么?
-Ingrid.  -What?
她叫英格丽,是我的女友
Her name is Ingrid  and she's my girlfriend.
英格丽可真不走运  因为我在这里
Well, bad luck, Ingrid,  'cause I'm here now.
天啊,你可听听你的语气吧?
Jesus Christ,  do you know how you sound?
我的语气‥?
How I sound? How I sound?
我此生从未见过你
I've never seen you before  in my life,
突然你跟我说你是我妻子
and now you're telling me  you're my wife.
听起来不觉得可怕又疯狂吗?
Doesn't that sound a tiny bit  scary mad to you?
既然我又可怕又疯癫  你怎么还跟我上床?
Well, if I'm a scary mad person,  why did you have sex with me?
-说实话这不需要什么理由吧  -去死
Well, to be honest I'd  never need that good a reason. Fuck you!
你乐意和疯女人上床?
So, you're happy  to fuck crazy women?
我若不愿意就会少了很多机会
Well, it would seriously  limit my options if I wasn't. Wouldn't it!
-王八蛋  -可是我还想再见到你
-Fuck you! None of which means  I don't wanna see you again.
我还会再见到你吗?
-When will I see you again?
不久的六天后,9月29日
-Soon. Six days. September 29th.
别担心,我要消失前总会这样
Now, don't worry. I always get like this  when I'm about to disappear.
你会习惯的,你会看到很多次
But you'll get used to it.  You'll see it lots of times.
下次带笔记本来  我会列出日期给你
Bring a notebook next time,  I'll give you a list of dates--
该死
Fuck.
去死
-Fuck you!  -Ah! Jesus Christ...
-你乐意和疯女人上床?  -天啊
So, you're happy  to fuck crazy women?
我若不愿意就会少了很多机会
Well,  it would seriously limit  my options if I wasn't.
-王八蛋  -该死‥
Fuck you!
混账,去死吧,亨利
Fuck, fuck, fuck... Fucking men.
该死的混账
Fucking asshole.
-克蕾儿‥  -混账
-Clare!  -Clare!  Asshole.
混账
Asshole.
「亨利28岁和36岁」
混账
Asshole.
♪ Shock me  Like an electric eel ♪
♪ Baby girl ♪
♪ Turn me on  With your electric feel ♪
请用
Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你好  -不好
-Hey.  -No.
♪ All along the Eastern shore ♪
♪ Put your circuits in the sea ♪
♪ This is what  The world is for ♪
♪ Making electricity ♪
♪ You can feel it  In your mind ♪
不要
No.
我说的不是真心话
Well, I didn't mean  any of those things I said.
是真心话
Yeah, you did.
我一路跑来要告诉你这件事
So, I ran all the way here to tell you that,
但我却傻站在外面  透过窗户看了你十分钟
but then, uh... being stupid, I just stood  outside and watched you at the window  for about ten minutes.
十分钟?  我才刚坐下
Ten minutes?  I only just sat down.
你好
Hi.
♪ He deals the cards  As a meditation ♪
法语单字背得如何?
How are  those French verbs coming?
♪ And those he plays  Never suspect ♪
我好想你
-I've missed you.
-你才刚和我上过床  -我没有‥
-Well, you just slept with me.
并没有
-No. No, I didn't.
拜托,你才找上了年轻小子  你觉得我怎么样?
-Hey, come on. You just got yourself  a new young man. What kind of guy  do you think I am?
结果是个混账
As it turns out, an asshole.
这是你这么多年来  一直对我隐瞒的秘密吗?
Was that the big secret,  you were keeping from me all these years?
你其实是个混账?
You're a secret asshole?
算是每个男人的秘密吧
It's kind of every man's secret.
那是我的杰作吗?
-Was that me?  -Oh.
没错
Yeah.
你第一次朝我丢鞋子
The first time  you threw a shoe at me.
我还是不觉得抱歉
I'm still not sorry.
我边长大边等你,想要你
I grew up waiting for you.  Longing for you.
-我知道  -你才不知道
-I know.  -No, you don't.
我的人生以你为中心  以你的形象为基
I formed myself around you.  The idea of you.
结果你却是个混账
And you're an asshole.
♪ Money for this art ♪
♪ That's not the shape... ♪
好吧,你听好
-Well here's the thing.
你以那个男人为中心
The man you formed  yourself around,
对方结果居然也以你为中心
shock twist,  formed himself around you.
-简直乱七八糟  -这个乱七八糟有个名字
-That's fucked up.  -Yep. So fucked up, it has a name.
婚姻
Marriage.
♪ He may lay  The queen of spades ♪
两个人试图成为对方认为的样子
Two people trying to be  the person the other one already thinks they are.
-这就是爱  -你没听到他说什么
Love, basically. You didn't hear  what he just said.
克蕾儿,我说了他说的话
Clare, I said what he just said.
你想知道我为什么这么说吗?
You wanna know why I said it?
因为时空旅行糟透了  可怕到不行
Because time travel is awful.  It is shit scary.
就像等着下场风暴来袭  不知道这次是否会害死你
It is waiting for the next storm  to hit. Wondering if this time  it's gonna kill you.
外面那个男生  时空旅行从未善待过他
That boy out there.  Time travel has never done one nice thing for him.
♪ And find out to their cost ♪
直到今天  今天他赢得了彩票头奖
Until today. Today he gets the winning  lottery ticket.
-那他为什么这么混‥  -知道什么比终日惶惶更糟吗?
-So, why is he being such-- -You know, what's even worse, than being terrified  all the time?
未来
The future.
未来是世界上最可怕的东西
The future is the scariest thing  in the world.
因为突然间你就到了未来
Because suddenly,  you are all in.
♪ Swords of a soldier... ♪
你毫无选择的余地
No choice.
除了希望  人能忍受各种折磨
Anyone can stand any kind  of torture, except hope.
那他为何不把这一切说出来?
Why didn't he just say all that?
他说了
He did.
只是花了我一点时间
It just took me a while.
♪ That's not the shape  Of my heart ♪
这件外套真丑
That's a shit jacket.
劫匪没得选
Well... Muggers can't be choosers.
现在你要回家了
And now you're off home.
对,再过一下子
In a minute, yeah.
-去找年纪大一点的我?  -去找我的妻子
-To older me?  -To my wife.
-王八蛋  -抱歉
-Bitch.  -Sorry?
年纪大的我有了你  但我只能有年轻的你
Older me gets you.  And I get younger you,
而他是混蛋,不公平
who's a dick. It's not fair.
他不是混蛋,你明明知道
No, he's not a dick.  And you know that.
他不是你
He's not you.
说真的他怎么变成你的?
Seriously,  how does he get to be you?
他发生了什么事?
What happens to him? Does he--
他‥是被陨石击中了吗?
Does he get hit  by a fucking meteorite?
对啊,陨石就叫做克蕾儿
Yeah, going by the name  of Clare.
这是称赞吗?
That a compliment?
我说你是陨石,随你怎么看
I just called you a meteorite.  Take it any way you like.
往好处想他比我性感多了
Hey. Look on the bright side.  He is way hotter than me.
-他才没有  -他一定有
-No, he's not.  -Sure, he is.
没关系,我不介意
It's okay. I don't mind.
其实我和你看法一致  我也搞过他
In fact, I agree with you.  I've fucked him, too.
为我点一杯威士忌苏打吧
I'll have a whiskey and soda.
-亨利  -亨利
-Henry.  -Henry.
-英格丽过得如何?  -她很好
-How's Ingrid?  -Good.
今晚可能会去找她  因为这次可不太顺利
Might go see her tonight, since  this isn't working out.
我以为已经挺顺利了
I thought it was working out  pretty well already.
管好你自己就好
Mind your own business.
-我不是要给建议  -千万不要
-Not that I'd ever offer advice.  -God forbid.
有个无趣的老人  很久以前跟我说过
But a boring old man  told me something a very long time ago.
你在地球上有两件事要做
He said you have two things to  do with your time on this Earth.
一是找到人生挚爱
One, find the love of your life.
二是死得越晚越好
Two, die as slowly as possible.
你今晚完成了第一件事
You did part one tonight.
第二件事现在才开始  游戏时间结束了
Part two starts now.  Play time is over.
你听自己说的话都不腻吗?
Do you ever get bored  of hearing yourself talk?
不好说,你自己体会吧
I don't know.  You tell me.
没有时间浪费了,小子
No more time to waste, junior.
你看过血就该知道有事要发生
You've seen the blood,  you know something's coming.
对,但不会是今天
Yeah. But not today.
你滚蛋的时间到了
Oh. Time for you  to fuck off then.
剪个头发吧
Get a haircut.
「亨利36岁」
「亨利36岁  克蕾儿28岁」
你回到什么时候了?
When were you?
很抱歉朝你丢鞋子
I'm sorry  I threw my shoe at you.
也是时候了
-Well, it's about time.  -Hmm.
「克蕾儿20岁」
「亨利28岁」
有人吗?  亨利?
Hello. Henry?
很久以前,男人出海  女人等着他们
Long ago,  men went to sea and women waited for them.
站在海边
Standing on the edge  of the water,
望着地平线看着迷你的船只
scanning the horizon  for the tiny ship.
现在则是我等着亨利
Now, I wait for Henry.
不会是今天,不要是今天
Not today.  Not today.
我讨厌去她不在的地方
I hate to be where she is not.
我却总是去向别处而她来不了
And yet I'm always going  and she can't follow.
为何他总是去我到不了的地方?
Why does he always go  where I cannot follow?